Marie Bourne

Manitowoc, WI 54220

Phone: 414-627-4246 | Email: m.bourne2@comcast.net

LinkedIn: linkedIn: linkedIn: linkedin.com/in/marie-bourne/

GitHub: github.com/BourneID7 | github.com/bourneidBH | Portfolio: bourneid7.github.io/portfolio/

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with 2+ years of experience and a background in visual design. Effective at combining UI design skills with backend logic to develop elegant, user-friendly applications. Known for attention to detail and the determination to see projects through regardless of obstacles.

Skills

HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript | NodeJS | MySQL | MongoDB | React | NextJS | PHP | Git | Photoshop Problem Solving | Creativity | Teamwork | Adaptability | Time Management | Attention to Detail

Experience

Freelance Software Developer Smart Interactive Media

May 2023 – Present

Milwaukee, WI

Freelance developer working on a variety of front-end UI/UX website improvements and backend development projects. Technologies: JavaScript, React, CSS WordPress, PHP.

Key Accomplishments:

Developed custom WordPress plugin to find customer products that fit specific semi-trailer
models

Software Developer Braustin Homes

Nov 2020 – Mar 2023

San Antonio, TX

Full stack developer responsible for both front-end and back-end development on public facing websites and internal sales portal applications. Technologies: NodeJS, JavaScript, React, SCSS, NextJS, GatsbvJS, WordPress, GraphQL, MongoDB.

Key Accomplishments:

Led code development for replatform and redesign project of corporate website in
collaboration with visual designer.
Created "Design Studio" web application to visualize mobile home model upgrade options
Led code development for replatform and redesign of internal sales portal. Added new
backend API service for generating forms and custom documents.

Creative Manager Harken. Inc.

2000 - Nov 2020

Pewaukee, WI

Creative manager and lead designer of a team of 5, overseeing and creating designs for monthly magazine advertising, trade show display graphics, brochures, catalogs, websites, and email marketing. Build effective cross-functional teams that unite creative designs with technical writing and specifications, ensuring on-time delivery of multilanguage global reach projects.

Kev	Accomplishments:	
	Directed design and drove project management of new mobile-responsive website including implementing content management and product database connection in 5 languages on-time and on-budget.	
	Led website redesign project, combining 13 separate international websites into 1 consistently branded multilingual website.	
	Envisioned and created architecture for product information management database to maximize shared information across diverse product lines of over 5000 products.	
	Modernized print catalog production and eliminated duplicate work between print and web projects by integrating product database with InDesign for 50% increase in efficiency.	
	Saved \$10K per year in outside photography fees and enabled photography of fast turnaround custom products by developing in-house studio for product photography.	
	Led team creative sessions, critiques and facilitated daily workflow as teacher/mentor in design and technology.	
	Built brand consistency by developing brand guidelines and providing art direction and training for staff and freelance designers/photographers.	
	Projects	
Brau	stin Homes Public Website	
Deployed Project: https://www.findmymobilehome.com/		
	Users can search for mobile homes in inventory or visualize a custom build with the Design Studio and explore company blog content.	
	Responsible for front-end React code and SCSS built to design specs provided. All backend API queries.	
	Built using NextJS, Styled-Components, WordPress, and a MongoDB database accessed through GraphQL queries.	
	stin Homes Internal Sales Portal ate Repository and Authenticated Access Only	
	Authenticated sales seps can add customers, set up sales records for mobile home	
	purchases, generate required paperwork. Finance team can run commission reports. Responsible for frontend redesign, migration from React App to NextJS, backend	
Ц	functionality for generating documents.	
	NextJS frontend web application connected to NodeJS backend and MongoDB database using React-Query.	

Education

Coding Bootcamp Certificate: UW-Extension, Milwaukee, WI A 24-week intensive program focused on technical programming in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars.js & React.

Web Design Certificate: Milwaukee School of Engineering, Milwaukee, WI

Bachelor of Fine Arts: Cardinal Stritch University, Milwaukee, WI